## James Li

# Senior Web & Blockchain Developer

Go UP and never STOP

## **Education**

## **Faculty of Engineering**

The University of Honk Kong Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong / From May 2011 to May 2014

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Engineering)

# Work experience

## Senior Full-Stack Web Developer

Upwork.com San Francisco, California, United States / From March 2017 to October 2019

- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Liaised with back end developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO as needed.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software with complete accuracy.

## [Testimonials]

Not only was James's work on-time and to spec, he pays attention to improve the aesthetics of the site as well as the functionality. Throughout the entire process he is responsive, and willing to work through issues as they arise. It's obvious he takes tremendous pride in his work, and I wouldn't hesitate to recommend or work with him again.

## Software QA Engineer

Ecotrak, LLC California, United States / From October 2019 to June 2020

## [Remote] [LINK]

- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Created accurate and successful test scripts to manage automated testing of certain products and features.
- Identified performance bottlenecks in Ecotrak sites via personallydesigned monitoring tools.

#### [Testimonials]

We have the fortune of working with James on a very regular basis. Every single project is done in a timely fashion and is delivered exactly as is outlined. Beyond that, his development skills and expertise make him an invaluable part of our process. We absolutely offer our highest possible recommendation.

- ≥ secret0910star@gmail.com
- ♥ Hong Kong
- m Date of birth 06/21/1992
- 852 8120 9503

## About me

Senior Web Developer with about 7 years of experience in Web Development using HTML, CSS, and modern JavaScript frameworks and 2 years of experience in Ethereum and smart contracts development and integration using Solidity, Vyper, and Web3 libraries.

# Highlights

All-around team-player

Self-motivated & proactive mindset

Passionate about learning new tech stack

#### Skills

## HTML/CSS

Figma/PSD/XD/Zeplin to Responsive and Pixel-perfect Page

## Bootstrap/Tailwind CSS

Layout and Build Landing Pages

## Vue.js

Vue.js(2.x & 3.x) & Vuex & Vuetify

#### **MERN** stack

MongoDB + Express.js + React.js + Node.js

## React.js

Hooks & Redux & Next.js & Gatsby

# Work experience

#### **Senior Front-End Developer**

Douglas Parker Associates (Pty) Ltd. South Africa / From January 2017 to March 2017

## [Remote] [LINK]

- Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software.
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS,
  JavaScript.Collaborating closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery.
- Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable.
- Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool.
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- Documenting bug reports, tickets, and any code changes.

## [Testimonals]

James has crafted a beautiful work that is as practical as it is inspirational. With CSS3 Foundations, James has taken what is often a confusing subject and made it not only accessible to beginners, but also valuable to practitioners who are looking for guidance on the latest CSS techniques.

## Senior Full-Stack Web Developer

Freelancer.com Sydney, Australia / From July 2014 to January 2017

## [Core Skills]

- Front-End(HTML/CSS/React.js)
- Backend(Node.js/Express.js/Laravel)
- Database(MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite)
- Others(GitHub, SVN)

## [Testimonials]

Working with James was better than expected and we had really high expectations. He is an incredibly talented developer but what really makes him stand out is his work ethic and steady approach. Time after time, and without us asking, he added enhancements and improvements that resulted in a better end product for us and our clients.

#### Skills

Laravel + Vue.js

Laravel + MySQL + Vue.js

**Python** 

Django/Flask

Vyper/Solidity

Web3 Libraries